<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>San Diego Real Estate Video Blog with Scott Voak</title>
    <description>Our mission at Voak Homes is to be your best resource for San Diego real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Voak Homes, your professional San Diego Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 13:14:13 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 13:14:13 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Tools Investors Use to Determine the Quality of an Investment</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5ZAcn80LxDs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investors rely on three tools, at different levels, to discern whether or not something is a good investment. Today I’ll detail what those tools are and how they’re used.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Gross rent multiplier.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether for an individual home, duplex, triplex, or apartment, the gross rent multiplier is a basic mathematical equation that gauges value. To calculate it, you take the value of the home and divide it by the annual rent. The higher your quotient, the better. On the subject of rent-to-property-value ratio, this segues well into “the 1% rule.” This rule holds that the monthly rent coming in should be worth 1% of your purchase price. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Cap rate.&lt;/strong&gt; Investors with institutional investments such as apartment buildings, office buildings, or strip malls are most familiar with this. Calculating the cap rate will help you determine how the building is performing without taking financing into account. Here, you subtract total monthly expenses (utilities, property management, property taxes, etc.) from your total monthly rent, and multiply what’s left over by 12 to represent months of the year. From there, you divide that figure by the value of the building. This will give you your cap rate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Cash-on-cash return.&lt;/strong&gt; Individual investors are known to go off of this last measure. How this works is you subtract your mortgage payments from your net rent (refer back to cap rate). Once your mortgage has been subtracted, you’re left with the cash flow you’re bringing in. And, rather than dividing by building value, you divide by equity. The idea here is to measure how much cash you’re generating against how much you’re putting in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have further questions about any of the investment valuation tools I covered or for help with anything else investment related, please reach out and give me a call today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=%20http://localhost:4000/3-tools-investors-use-to-determine-the-quality-of-an-investment.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 09:20:03 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-tools-investors-use-to-determine-the-quality-of-an-investment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-tools-investors-use-to-determine-the-quality-of-an-investment.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Top 3 Problems With Zillow</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vznHhXUmeIU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zillow can be a valuable tool, but it definitely isn’t a perfect resource. Today we’ll be covering the top three problems people encounter when using this popular real estate website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the people I’ve met have a love/hate relationship with Zillow. While this popular real estate website can be a valuable tool, many of its features are deeply flawed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we’ll review three of the most common problems people encounter when using Zillow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Inaccurate home values.&lt;/strong&gt; 13% of all Zillow Zestimates are off by more than 10%. This could mean a difference of tens of thousands of dollars for Zillow’s higher-end listings. The reason for this discrepancy is that Zillow’s algorithm cannot account for certain key features of a home, like its location or how recently it has been updated. The information on Zillow is no replacement for what an experienced agent can tell you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Outdated information.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers using Zillow will often find a listing they love only to find out later from their agent that this property sold months ago. Much of the data you’ll find on Zillow is old, and should be taken with a grain of salt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The information on Zillow is no replacement for what an experienced agent can tell you.%20http://localhost:4000/the-top-3-problems-with-zillow.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The information on Zillow is no replacement for what an experienced agent can tell you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Misleading advertising for “Coming Soon” listings.&lt;/strong&gt; People get excited about these supposedly exclusive properties when they see them online, but often fail to account for the fact that this arrangement will require them to work directly with the listing agent representing it. Some might assume that forgoing representation of their own is worthwhile, but this is seldom the case. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 13:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-top-3-problems-with-zillow.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-top-3-problems-with-zillow.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Causing the Slowdown in Our Real Estate Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/g9XKZVl86S4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our real estate market is starting to soften a bit. Some of it is typical of the season, but not all of it is.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got a quick update for you today on the San Diego real estate market: November continued a downward trend in activity and sales prices for San Diego County. You can easily break the market up into two segments: attached and detached homes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attached home market saw the biggest hit. The number of sales was down by about 20%, but what was more alarming to me was the price reductions. &lt;strong&gt;We have seen a 6% drop in prices in the last two months and the median price is currently only 1% over last year.&lt;/strong&gt; At the same time, we have 40% more homes on the market than we did last year. This is adding to pressure to drive prices down. Expect to see prices continue to drop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As for detached homes, that segment of the market is faring much better.&lt;/strong&gt; Prices were down for the third consecutive month, but in those three months combined, we’re only seeing about a 3.5% decline and we’re still 9% above where we were last year. We’re seeing softness here, but most of it’s seasonal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The attached home market saw the biggest hit.%20http://localhost:4000/whats-causing-the-slowdown-in-our-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The attached home market saw the biggest hit.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When trying to determine what’s going on in the attached home market, we’re seeing a seasonal slowdown in price reduction that’s compounded by a couple of other factors, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Interest rates.&lt;/strong&gt; With lower-priced homes, we tend to see many first-time buyers who are using larger loans and putting less money down. As rates are going up, these people are being affected much more. In the luxury home market, those buyers are paying more in cash and with large down payments, so the rates are not affecting them as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Taxes.&lt;/strong&gt; Nobody really knows what these new tax laws will mean until we get our taxes back in April. A lot of people are saying that they’ll wait until they see what’s on their tax return this year. Will they have extra money or will they owe more money? Expect some of this inventory logjam to get reduced as we get closer to tax day and these questions are answered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Tax law.&lt;/strong&gt; With the increase in the standard deduction and the reduction in the number of deductions you can take for your mortgage interest and state taxes, it has taken away a lot of the benefits of homeownership. You have to have a mortgage above $400,000 before your mortgage interest deduction will exceed the standard deduction. For right now, expect the bottom of the market to stay soft because of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would expect the attached market to stay soft throughout the next year and the detached market to ebb and flow per usual, depending on the time of year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the best news for a lot of people, but it is creating opportunities for certain people in certain segments. If you’d like to talk about how you might be able to benefit from the current conditions, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 13:45:54 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-causing-the-slowdown-in-our-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/whats-causing-the-slowdown-in-our-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Real Estate Market Update for November</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GNTRZ0UwW_U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our latest market update shows that it isn’t exactly the best time for you buyers out there.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’ll be taking a look at the market changes we’ve seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent sales were interesting from a statistical standpoint. Inventory is still higher than last year with a 30% to 35% increase. However, there was a slight reduction from previously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of sales has increased; &lt;strong&gt;we’re seeing some acceleration at a time of year when things are usually slowing down.&lt;/strong&gt; It seems people who were out of the market are taking advantage of the slowdown and jumping back in. We’ve seen home pricing hold and stay fairly steady. You’ll soon be hearing from the Association of Realtors that median prices have fallen substantially, with some areas seeing a 4% to 5% decrease in a single month. However, the mean pricing has held up well. If the median is dropping and the mean is staying the same, it shows we’re selling more higher-priced homes and fewer entry-level homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because interest rates are up. Cheaper homes are geared toward younger buyers who have less to put down and rising rates have really hurt this part of the market. &lt;strong&gt;Expect this to continue.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sellers really need to prepare homes with minor renovations such as paint and carpet. Buyers have no extra money to do repairs like this after purchasing, so make sure they’re happy with what they see. It’s very important to showcase your home well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’re a buyer waiting for the bubble to pop, it’s not going to.%20http://localhost:4000/real-estate-market-update-for-october.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’re a buyer waiting for the bubble to pop, it’s not going to.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a buyer waiting for the bubble to pop, it’s not going to. People have too much equity in their houses and demand is low. Sellers who really have to move are having to come down by 3% to 4% to get buyers excited. However, there are too many buyers and these homes are grabbed immediately. You won’t find 15% to 20% drops in this market. &lt;strong&gt;Although, if you’re patient and willing to take a less-than-perfect home, you can get a great deal.&lt;/strong&gt; Sellers who didn’t go all out to showcase their homes are getting a little desperate because nobody’s interested. Buyers can take advantage of this, especially before the holiday season hits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need help buying or selling a home, have any questions, or would like some further information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 10:41:11 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/real-estate-market-update-for-october.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/real-estate-market-update-for-october.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Valuable New Resource For You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6Lwkv6qFiFg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to welcome you to my new video blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my blog, you’ll find tips for both buyers and sellers in the real estate market, as well as updates on what’s happening in our local market. The real estate market affects all of us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really want this page to be a valuable resource for you. If you have any questions about our market or about real estate in general, send me an email. Odds are good that if you have a question about a topic, someone else does as well; so, send your questions my way and we’ll make an educational video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look around. I look forward to hearing from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 10:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-valuable-new-resource-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-valuable-new-resource-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
